Guide to the Patricia Vinnicombe Yakotis Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Patricia Vinnicombe Yakotis papers
1946-1952
SC0699
Yakotis, Patricia Vinnicombe.
2.75 Linear feet
Collection includes class materials, notes, and some papers from her classes at Stanford, 1946-49, in particular history, political science, and French literature and culture; a scrapbook of student memorabilia and photographs, 1946-49; and a few personal papers including portraits and a letter from a priest concerning the reading of banned books. Of note in the scrapbook are Big Game Gaieties programs, 1946 and 1949, and a booklet of cartoons by Barbara Allen entitled STANFORD TRADITIONS.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Patricia Vinnicombe Yakotis earned her A.B. in political science at Stanford University in 1950.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes class materials, notes, and some papers from her classes at Stanford, 1946-49, in particular history, political science, and French literature and culture; a scrapbook of student memorabilia and photographs, 1946-49; and a few personal papers including portraits and a letter from a priest concerning the reading of banned books. Of note in the scrapbook are Big Game Gaieties programs, 1946 and 1949, and a booklet of cartoons by Barbara Allen entitled STANFORD TRADITIONS.
Access Terms
Allen, Barbara.; Vinnicombe, Patricia.; Yakotis, Patricia Vinnicombe.; Scrapbooks
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Art classes:
    - History of Painting (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Asian-Slavic classes:
    - Russian Literature, 1948 (includes her paper, Comparison of Philosophies of Dostoievsky and St. Francis of Assisi) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biology classes:
    - Biology 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Biology 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Biology, miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business classes:
    - Typing Assignments (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - English classes:
    - English 2A, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - English notes (Modern British Humorists and Contemporary British Prose), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wilde's Conception of Art and Beauty – paper for Modern British Humorists (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Shakespeare (English 25), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History classes:
    - American History, syllabi, class handouts, etc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American History, notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - British Empire, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - British Empire, book 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - European History – handouts (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - European History – notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Humanities classes:
    - Religion (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Law classes:
    - Business Law, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy classes:
    - Philosophy 5, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Political Science classes:
    - American Government (Political Science 1), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - American Government (Poli Sci 2) – syllabi, handouts, papers (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - American Government (Poli Sci 2) – notes (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - American Public Law, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Contemporary World Politics, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Foreign Affairs Journals [source materials] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Governments, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Governments paper: Italy (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Service (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Service paper: Ambassador Davies (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - International Law 130, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - International Law paper: Monroe Doctrine, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Latin America and the U. S. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Political Parties, notebook, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Political Parties, note cards, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Reading reports, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Reading reports, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Seminar in International Relations (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Should Hawaii Have Statehood? (paper for unspecified class) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - State Department (Poli Sci 230) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - State Department (Poli Sci 230): reports by R. Huff (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - State Department (Poli Sci 230): reports by L. B. Ruscigne (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - State Department (Poli Sci 230): reports by Carl G. Winter (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Psychology classes:
    - Psychology 51 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Romanic Languages classes:
    - French 135 Rousseau / French 152 Modern novel (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - French 145 Contemporary literature (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - French 150, Literature (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - French Comedy (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - French Modern Drama (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - French Civ (1 of 2), 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - French Civ (2 of 2,) 1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - French Mystiques (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Social Problems of France (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Political Problems of France (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous:
    - Miscellaneous class materials (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous course information (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Personal papers, including photograph and portrait of Patricia Vinnicombe and a letter from a priest regarding the reading of banned books (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Personal Scrapbook:
    - Loose items from scrapbook (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Big Game Gaieties programs, 1946, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Saturday Evening Post, Oct. 15, 1949 (has article on Stanford's football coach, Marchmont Schwartz) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sophomore Carnival placard (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Ten Views of Stanford in Color, published by the Stanford University Press (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Tournament of Roses program, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook of student memorabilia, 1946-48 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - RESTRICTED MATERIALS
    - Exams and grade reports (Box 6)